Hello, folks.
I'm here.
Folks, can you hear me?
I can hear you.
Oh, good.
Okay.
Because you're all dark and on mute.
I was like, Gary, saying one sec.
Let me turn on the lights.
Just need time to create the Titanic battle.
Really?
Titanic?
This?
Where's the drama?
I'll give you drama.
Give me a second.
I got prepared.
There's drama.
I like other people's drama.
You're the drama.
I'm drama?
In this quest, you are the drama.
Oh, well, yes.
Okay.
But in general, I'm not.
What, buddy?
Get out of here.
Can you have advantage and disadvantage on initiative?
Advantage on initiative?
What does that even mean?
Well, twice.
You get a plus five.
I mean, it's just a bonus, not advantage, right?
Yeah, interesting.
What are you talking about?
I don't know whether I approve of this.
Well, according to DD Beyond, maybe if you use a heroic inspiration on your initiative, you get a plus five.
Oh, well, that makes sense.
That does actually.
Seems pretty tame.
What is going on behind you, Gary?
She has a dog that is a squishable thing, so she was stepping on it.
Cute puppy.
How's it get along with the cats?
Yeah.
I thought you were in Bedseria.
Okay, goodbye.
Wow, that was very passive-aggressive there, Gary.
Here I was trying to include her.
Well, well done.
Very well done.
I haven't seen Arlo in a long time.
All right.
Did anybody read the summary?
Does anybody remember?
There was no summary.
Something.
Yeah, there was.
There was a summary.
There was even a summary of the summary.
I got a preview.
Oh, there was a thread.
Yeah.
Dude, Google Chat is useless.
It's always a thread.
That's why I didn't find it.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Google Chat is.
Yeah.
I read this.
I had some fun with it.
I'm selling out.
Yes.
I think maybe I am selling out.
We'll see how that goes.
I thought, you know, it wasn't the dialogue, just for the record.
Yeah, no, no, no.
No.
You didn't make anything up.
I approved the summary.
Whenever you're ready.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay, so I just suddenly was rereading the thing I wrote.
I'm like, it was kind of fun.
All right.
Okay.
Let's see if we get.
Oh, man.
I'm logged out.
Oh, oh, oh, there's like, there's some.
Oh, Gary, I can now answer the question of the dueling character sheets.
Dueling character sheets.
Okay.
So the guy who works on Beyond 20, right, who gets paid no money and does this as a free service, has a bug in his code, which he refuses to fix.
Which he refuses to fix.
I mean, I'm being an asshole person complaining about somebody who does something for free that doesn't get paid, right?
Yeah, his priorities, and this is an unpaid priority.
Yeah.
And so it doesn't work if you have more.
There's a bug that if you have two things open, it only recognizes one.
But only character sheets, right?
Because I'm always pulling open monster sheets and it's fine.
For character sheets, it only recognizes one.
But it used to work.
Yes, there's a bug in his code.
There's a bug in the new code.
Yes, yes.
Well, or there was a change in regression.
There was a regression, and his test harness was inadequate.
And frankly, I don't know why he isn't prioritizing this over whatever else he thinks might be important, including.
Well, you got a bug.
The first thing you do is roll back.
You don't try to push forward.
I think the problem is not that he has a bug, but that DD Beyond changed this interface and he hasn't figured out how to debug this code yet.
Rolling back in production is a serious hassle, too, because usually there's a database migration that you then have to unwind and sometimes can't.
Yeah.
So regardless.
Does Beyond 20 require a database migration?
It might.
I mean, it's got a whole bunch of whenever you add new features.
So I have side, right?
Like all your stuff is in the cloud.
Like, I don't have anything local.
Yeah.
So I don't know.
So regardless, regardless of the situation, I just thought everybody should know that there is a bug.
I have identified the bug, and I'm very disappointed with this free volunteer's inability to focus on what matters.
You could voluntarily buy him a coffee.
Oh, I've already bought him coffee before.
I mean, like.
I bought him a cup of coffee, so he owes me.
Stick coffee in, get code out.
I mean, that's the.
No, I was just kind of encouraging him to keep the product updated.
That was why I did.
Okay.
I don't know.
So, yeah, so there's some bug.
I mean, if I really wanted to, I guess I could open up two different windows that are in different browsers.
Two browsers, yeah.
Or, you know, you could, you know, go read the code and fix the bug.
Oh, well.
Yeah, you do that too.
Is it actually, is there a repo that we could actually fix it ourselves?
Yeah, there's.
Well, Mr.
Well, Mr. Retiree here might have some free time.
All right.
I have 10 more days until I'm free again.
Oh, I am.
I am unfortunately going to India for two weeks and a week and a half.
Well, that didn't stop you from playing last time.
Yes, I will certainly endeavor to make an attempt.
Shame you into it.
Well, shame it didn't stop you last time.
It should work, but just kind of like warning about the chaos impending.
Oh, okay.
It works.
All right.
So the party enters.
Let's see.
Let me just get everything set up.
Okay.
So let me just see if I can.
You step into a clearing relatively approximately 60 feet across.
Cross, but something feels wrong.
The dense woods surround you.
Stop leaning forward unnaturally, your twisted bark gleaming like obsidian in the faint, eerie light filtering through the broken canopy above.
Pools of iridescent sap shimmer at scattered points, their colors shifting hypnotically.
The thick underbrush your feet is blackened and thorny, stagging at your armored skin.
At the heart of the clearing stands an immense tree and like figure, its limbs bending in impossible geometries, dripping glowing sap into a pool nearby.
Near it, faint, flickering tears in reality, pulse near it, near it, faint, flickering tears in reality, paul softly, whispering promises of power and madness.
So you also notice it does not sound like fair trade power.
I hope the promise of madness is not like a you know, like a bait and switch because we need that madness.
I disagree.
I didn't need the madness.
All right, okay.
Okay.
All righty.
So we agree, Gary.
Neither of us wants the power.
All right.
Fair enough.
You also notice members are obviously members of the Emerald Enclave.
It's the first party.
My fans.
One of them shouts.
They are.
They will be soon.
Yeah, of course.
Let's see.
They're currently trapped in the.
They're currently trapped.
It's almost as if the treant has controlled the brambly woods to yeah.
Okay, so yes, I need to put some monsters.
138 hit points.
Woo!
No, no, it's not that.
No, no, that's that's a little bit different.
Oh, you're you're not following the monster manual.
That is prerogative.
Oh, wow.
No creativity allowed.
We play fourth edition where you're not allowed to make decisions.
All right.
16 hit points.
The treant, it's 110.
Oh, okay.
All right.
But you're supposed to have, you know, you're, you know.
So, Lyra, so the woman here shouts, sees you, notices that Soma is a druid.
Soma is a bear.
Oh, Soma's a bear?
I never took the form off.
Oh, okay.
I'm counting on you to keep track of the hour.
I have an idea.
All right.
Do you want to hear what she says, or do you want to like, you know, no, no, no, no, no.
Yeah.
Okay.
I just have an idea.
All right.
Help us.
So she goes, My name is Lyra.
We're out of the Emerald Enclave.
This thing, it was the Grove's Guardian, but it has been corrupted.
We are trying to sever a planar infection when it turned on us.
Please, you have to fight it.
Don't let the corruption spread.
Okay.
So, Soma, can you understand common when you're a bear?
My understanding is that, yes, you can.
Yeah.
Let me just check.
I mean, sometimes you have to communicate as a bear before you do your deed.
Definitely.
All right.
We've got characters in.
You're a bear, right?
Is that what I heard?
I'm a bear.
Find Soma the bear.
Soma Bear.
Yeah, you can understand, but you can't speak.
Okay, that's what I thought.
Yeah, so I'm kind of mute.
I can roar.
But if somebody else casts speak with animals, then they can understand you.
Yeah.
I mean, I can also just drop.
I have got shapes out the wazoo because of the subclass.
All right, well, I'm ready to cast a spell when I'm allowed to do that.
Oh, I guess I should roll initiative.
Yeah, so your people should roll initiative.
All right.
What's that?
An 11?
There we go.
15.
Looks like you'll be first then, Mr.
Spellcaster.
It works.
I can't move.
My last hit points were.
So it's my understanding that the tree is holding the party.
Is that it?
The druids from the Emerald Enclave holding them?
Well, the elves are currently restrained by thick, thorny vines.
You cannot.
Yes.
Okay, so let me see.
All right, let's go.
Let me go to the initiative die rule.
Just so the record, the yeah, maybe you can explain to me what's going on here.
So there's one, two, and three.
Hold on, give me a second to just make sure.
Okay.
Initiative.
There's a roll-off between me and Blueberry.
Blueberry?
Blueberry.
Natural one.
All right.
Well, it might be the case that
I rolled a six, so that means you rolled a five.
All right, let's actually do it.
10.5.
No.
I think 10.5.
Treant gets 10.5.
10.
Yeah, sorry, 10.5, and this guy gets 10.5.
Right.
Yeah, that looks right.
All right, let me just sort again.
There we go.
All right.
Okay.
The various ensnared folks can't do anything until you remove them from their ensnarement, just so you know.
All right.
So you were asking questions.
All right, Dave.
So here's what's going on.
You have these magical wells.
I haven't put the word well on all of them, but let me just so that there's no confusion later.
I will just
another well over here.
Well, well, well.
All right.
These are magical wells.
Should we put the thorns on the initiative tracker?
The thorns, thorns can only attack you when you enter within 10 feet of them.
Understood.
But the thorns are what are holding the elves.
So to free the elves, we would have to destroy the thorns.
Yes.
Okay, so they should be on the tracker because bringing the elves so they can participate in fighting the treant seems prudent.
Yeah, no, no, I'm just trying to think.
Do they need to be?
Yeah.
All right.
Let me just get the initiative.
They could probably also cast spells.
No, they can't.
They cannot cast while ensnared.
They're being held.
They're out of spell points.
No, they're not out of spell points.
They can't move.
No, they can't do somatic components.
Yes.
So they're kind of caught in it.
That's why they're kind of feeling a little bit out of story.
Bucks dive on me.
All right.
Let's not give them.
They will not have.
Let me see if my.
Unfortunately, I think I did something to do Google Docs that caused it to crash, which is very nice.
So for this encounter, the Brambles will not attack.
They will just be grappling the creatures.
They are currently focused on that.
Okay.
I don't see myself on the board.
That's because I put two Valfines and not one Bukradin because I am dyslexic and I get confused.
Maybe you don't know why the fairy should be not near Brambles.
All right.
So.
The elves, are they all equal, or is there one that's like the leader?
Okay, who's the mass?
You find the head druid.
You can ask.
Who's in charge here?
Yeah, who's in charge here?
She goes, who are you?
I'm helping Soma the bear.
Is it that fancy icon in the top right?
Yeah, so it goes, I am Lyra.
I am the lead of this group.
Okay.
Lyra's.
She is ensnared by.
So this thing that's in snare, this is one Bramble that's trapped two creatures.
Three.
Is that correct?
Yeah, yeah, it's crapped two.
Sorry.
Yeah, it seems to be the primary target then.
All right.
I mean, yeah, go for it.
Command drop.
Wisdom save.
Do you had to do something like that?
So now I have to go figure out what the stat block is.
Thank you.
All right.
Oh, wait, can you only command things that are sentient?
Like, anyway, does any creature, and it must, oh, yeah, we discussed this.
Brambles are creatures.
We used, we, yes, we used this last week.
Yeah, no, it's not.
Anything that it is holding.
I get it.
I'm not disputing it.
I'm just executing it a little.
No, I'm trying to find.
You'll probably make the save and it'll be moved.
Here we go.
Blighted vine.
All right.
So, but they're all right.
Five.
I found it.
Okay.
It's been a day.
I will just, all the blighted vines attack at the same time.
You're declaring it to be one monster.
All right.
14.
Okay.
So it's okay.
So you do blight, you tell it to blighted, you tell it to release the creatures.
All right.
What's my saving throw?
I think I figured this out a second ago.
It's a wisdom saving throw, and it's got a plus zero.
It's higher than I'd expect.
Better than 50%.
Oh, hold on.
Hold on.
Does command require.
Oh, yeah.
Does it need to be able?
Do you need to be able to communicate in its language?
It's like the interesting question.
I made the saving throw.
As predicted.
You knew it wasn't going to work.
Why did you do it?
Because this is Bukradin, and he has these ego thing where instead of actually damaging things, he wants to give command performances and declare to people what needs to happen.
Is that it?
I was really helping you just viciously mock them, but you know.
They probably would have made that save too.
All right.
Roll 17.
You can make lots of saves.
The creature, the blighted vines hold on to everyone.
The treant, as you stare at the treant, or you look at the treant, or you notice the treant in a way that guarantees you will not be accidentally inflicted by any diseases or whatnot.
What you notice is a detiring treant whose bark is glossy obsidian, obsidian, weeping, iridescent sap.
Its limbs bend into impossible angles, and its voice echoes with overlapping whispers.
Its movements are less like a living plant and more like a glitch in reality.
So it looks like it's been somehow twisted by some kind of planar energies.
All right.
Okay.
Since nobody's within 10 feet, the vines just hold on to them.
Apparently, the treant is amused to watch Lyra and her compatriots trapped.
Okay.
Who's next?
I think that's me.
All right.
So I think I entered this range.
Does anybody tell her tell them that you guys are that she's a druid, or are you guys going to just pretend that she's your friendly neighborhood pet bear?
Druids are smart like that.
Let her figure it out on her own.
Fine.
She's not going anywhere.
Yeah, okay.
I enter the vines.
Do they attack when I get in range, or is that a.
Yeah, yeah, they do.
They do.
All right.
Yes, they attack DC 20 plus four.
They hit for four points of damage.
Oh, dear.
I don't know if that's a deer.
Oh, bear.
But, yes.
All right.
Then, yeah, we're going to take a couple of swings at those guys.
First hit.
Let's make this public.
And that looks like a.
Let's see.
On the blighted vine, they're a 12, so that's a miss.
Second attack.
Ooh, I hit myself.
Gonna be one of those days.
The treant laughs.
Look, I'm not used to being a bear, alright?
I'm sorry.
There were just so many things that went through my twisted and sick head at that point.
Did you take damage there?
I took some.
Yeah, I meant 25 out of 20.
All right.
Okay.
Oh, I just didn't see it on the tracker.
Oh, sorry.
Yeah.
It's annoying because I get a lot of bonus HP every time I do this.
Oh, actually, I should have been at 27 plus 9 is 36.
Minus 4 is 32.
One of the other members of the group shouts, You there!
I don't know who you are, but you look capable.
We can reward you.
We have resources, information about the forces at play in this region.
Just get us out of these vines and help us put that core creature out of its misery.
Did they not realize that we're helping them?
You kind of cast a spell that hasn't done anything.
There's a bear.
I'm just saying this guy over here, he hasn't quite figured out that the bear is, you know.
Hey.
I will try to avoid being offended.
Okay.
I'm trying hard.
All right.
I'm digging deep on this one.
Fine.
Let me rewrite what he wrote.
All right, fine.
Okay.
What did you do, Gary?
Sorry, I'm just making Roll 20 icons for my thing, so I don't have to scramble.
Okay.
The Treant is up.
No, the Treant is up.
The Treant goes.
All right.
What does he do?
Trees don't talk.
What?
What's he?
Okay, so the Treant sort of.
The Treant looks at you and decides who goes, stay out of my grove.
If you stay out of my grove and let me be, then I will not attack you.
And so since you haven't quite entered the grove, he hasn't yet attacked you.
That's good.
Brewberry.
All right.
So I will grow.
Oh, boy.
And so I have 15 feet reach.
Nice.
You big boys.
All right.
What are you going to attack first?
This vine over here, which I can attack from well, out of its reach.
Yes.
And then to that do anything.
Brewberry Smash, bad guy.
With a nine attack roll.
Does it hit?
No, that's a miss.
Nope, none of us can hit it.
All right, Melfina, you want to take a stab at it?
Lyra, Lira goes, Miyoki has abandoned us.
Yeah, well.
We have lots of rounds.
Lyra looks at the...
Hold on.
Lyra looks at the drow and says,
Hey, this is mocking is my thing.
No, no, no.
No, no.
She says, a cleric of a drow that is a cleric of Lefender?
Can this be?
Why, yes!
He's gloriously painful with the lights.
Yes.
Okay.
Wait a second.
Hold on.
All right.
So I need to figure out something to do with my action.
And then I will do a thing.
And then
yes, I rolled a DC-13.
It's like Dexterity Save.
Oh, no, no, no.
Interesting.
So, like, some things are coming through with the Beyond 20, but not everything.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, anyway,
we can do.
Will that do something?
Guiding Bolt?
Yep, that hits.
That's a 14 guiding bolt.
Okay.
Did it roll damage?
14 damage?
Yep, 14 damage.
On the vines.
All right.
Okay, so they will go down to 12.
Yep.
And next person to attack them has advantage.
Should help.
I guess that's me.
Give it a shot.
Yeah.
I'm thinking about the best way to go here.
Command drop again.
Starry Whip.
That's a hit.
Yes, whispered.
That is a hit.
Even without it.
Well, I guess I have advantage, so I should probably roll it twice.
Okay, my crit.
Just in case I get a crit.
I do not.
All right.
Nice.
Jesus fucking Christ.
One of those nights.
This is going to be a long combat, I think.
Another other plans tonight.
All right, blighted vine.
Do you want to mock me?
You should.
I deserve it.
No.
No, instead, the blighted vine.
What will the blighted vine do?
You're 10 feet away.
Soma's here.
Everyone's far away.
Yeah, it's currently holding on to everybody.
It does.
Oh, what it does is it releases.
You sense it wants to do something, but it's kind of holding on to the two creatures, to the cute characters, and so strikes at Soma.
No, not Soma.
And it's, I think, for four points of damage.
16 is, yeah, that's what you need to hit.
Four points of damage.
Oh, wait.
Oh, no.
I think I inherit the Bears AC at 16.
Yeah, I'd be 17 in turtle form.
All right.
How much damage?
Four points of damage.
Taking me down to 28.
You almost got me to my base HP.
All right.
You're up, Soma.
Yeah, well, and I attack back.
Let's go.
Let's try not to do it.
I mean, I've been known to do it before.
Just, hey, there's a hit.
All right.
Awry with 12 damage.
Hooray!
Yes, you damage the vines.
Yay, that's the vine.
Except just this cluster.
All right.
So they're free, right?
Are they excited?
Hold on.
Well, those two are.
We'll get the other ones eventually.
Yeah, hold on.
Let me just.
Okay, so let me get.
I need to go figure this out.
Okay, so you got her out.
All right.
Her and elf one.
Yeah, her and elf one.
So,
all right.
So she explains.
What does she explain?
She says, we were in the midst of performing a ritual to perform a ritual.
And as a result of freeing her, she waves her little hand.
And four stones appear.
Do you like avant-garde music?
She looks at you as if you are insane.
Oh, what just appeared?
Okay, so she points.
She doesn't like music.
Everybody likes music.
All right.
Okay.
So what she says is we need to complete the ritual on the stones to clear, to seal the rift.
How do we do that?
What do we need to do?
Here.
She goes, she does point out that.
Okay, so here's it is.
All right.
Performing.
Okay, so it's pretty simple rules.
I'll just drop them into Google chat because that is the chat.
Okay.
Yes.
Well, I'm using Google Chat.
Here we go.
Whoa.
Fix ritual actions before accumulating three failures?
Yes.
Well, I at least get advantage on the wisdom ones.
We probably have some good clerical on the religion, right?
I can do sleight of hand.
Jesus, DC15 on the wisdom.
Even with advantage, it's going to suck.
You can use help.
So you can roll with advantage.
I roll with advantage naturally on that one.
Well, I mean, with help.
Three failures and we're out.
Wow.
And I already burned all my bardic inspirations.
So that's not good.
Well, not good.
All right.
Soma still has another attack.
So I guess we go try to free Elf 2 because he among these brambles.
Yes.
All right.
I'll still stay out of the Treant's grove.
I'm taking the long way around.
Let me just do this.
Sure.
We're just going to do this so that I can remember to keep these guys.
These guys are gone.
All right.
Is that what we're doing?
Yeah, is this sufficient to free ELF 2 over here if I want these?
Yes.
All right.
So that's, let's see, I did a bite so I have a claw yet.
Let me just add this one's at what 26?
Well, it's now 17 lower.
Okay.
No, I guess it's 11 lower.
11 lower.
All right.
15.
It's not a very good crit.
Oh, well.
All right, good.
You got it for me.
All right.
Yep.
Got it.
All right.
Treant.
Yeah, can I just add the Enclave Warriors?
Yeah, sure.
Yep.
Just let me just add 313.
No, no, that's not how many.
That's, you know, 13 and 16.
Sorry, I don't know what you want back.
Oh, I see.
AC16.
AC13.
You want to roll initiatives for them?
Yeah, I'm going to roll initiatives for them.
Give me.
They can join next round, I assume.
Yeah.
So I will just, we will skip over them until after Hukerdin.
Does that make sense?
Until after Balfina.
Okay, I don't know why it's doing this to me, but I don't know.
All right.
Okay.
So Treant is up.
Right.
Treant is up.
So you didn't free the other guy, right?
The other guy is not good.
Still nobody in the grove.
Well.
Yeah, we're staying on the outsides.
You're staying on the outsides.
Over these two guys are in the grove.
So the treant is pissed.
And what?
Why is he pissed?
Because the guys are in his grove.
The guys are in his grove.
And they're trying to, and they're trying to.
Oh, number one, Elf 1?
Yeah, and Lyra.
Oh, Lyra's not.
Lyra's outside of the grove.
He's outside.
But Elf 1 is inside.
I agree.
No, the grove is the circle around the trees.
Oh.
So as long as you're close to touching the trees, you're okay.
Oh, I see.
I see.
Okay, sorry.
He's not touching a tree.
Got it.
Yes.
And he screams, you think I'm wrong.
You think there is something wrong with me?
That I must be changed back.
I am.
And starts spewing all sorts of stuff about how he's happy to be powerful and dangerous and like people should respect his choices.
Well, conveniently.
I am a 50 feet.
I have respect.
All right, so he takes, he slams the guy most next to you.
Is this remote class?
Conclave warrior?
Yeah, he's not going to last long.
Yeah.
Meat shield.
Shield number one.
Shield number one gets hit twice.
He does.
So meat shield number one might be no more.
He did his job.
Takes 15 points of damage.
He's down to one hit point.
Oh, that's perfect.
That's perfect.
He takes one additional attack.
Oh, he'll have to have another round.
I love it.
All right, Bruberry, you're up, man.
Action economy.
Actual good news for once.
Seriously?
So, Roman hit us.
Did he die?
Of course that's good news.
No, no, no, no.
I'm just sorry.
I'm just going that he didn't die.
I'm like going, wait, you're a red shirt.
You're supposed to die.
It's supposed to be this dramatic.
Am I allowed to stand here?
On game.
What is this well thing again?
That's one of the planar wells.
So I don't want to stand on it, is what you're saying.
Yes.
If you stand on it, you risk madness.
You mean more than I am already.
You don't want to go do the ritual?
You don't want to do rituals?
Do the rituals?
You can run to try ritual.
Oh, I guess if you're raging, then you need to attack.
Yeah.
Yeah, I need to attack.
Okay.
Yeah, you and I will keep the brambles down.
Can I stand on this well?
No.
These are all the wells.
I just didn't use the same icon for them.
So one is four bucks.
But you can.
You just have to stand here.
Yes.
Wow.
Being large is some disadvantages.
Hold on, hold on.
You must roll a wisdom saving throw.
Yes.
Wisdom, you say.
Oh, wow.
With a minus one, even.
Barbarians always make their wisdom save.
You are insane, dude.
Have you told him about the other barbarian?
We played Curse of Strahd, and the barbarian.
I kept trying.
Strahd kept trying to command the barbarian, and he kept getting like 18, 19, and 20.
Good times.
Yes.
All right.
Okay.
So you do not get.
All right.
I don't get suspicious thing.
Okay, great.
Yeah.
All right.
There's an aura.
So hold on.
Let me just draw the aura for you guys.
You hadn't yet entered the aura.
So now that you have entered it for the first time, I should probably draw it out.
Around the treant?
Yes.
You could just apply it to the token, can't you?
Oh, yeah, that's right.
Sorry.
Why didn't I think of that?
Like that, like on Soma.
Yeah, yeah.
There.
That's the aura.
What's the aura?
We don't see it, though, unfortunately.
Oh, you don't?
Maybe because it's the wrong.
I chose the worst possible color.
How about now?
No.
No, that's weird.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh, well.
It was worth a shot.
Okay.
Okay, hold on.
You can just tell us.
It's all right.
Hey, there we see.
Yeah, I mean, that works.
All right, that works.
All right, hold on.
Well, it just vanished.
Yeah, I know.
I just need to get the right.
No, this is the wrong one.
All right, so we will use this one.
Maybe we'll use this one here.
There's the aura.
All right.
Okay.
Well, I assume 16 hits the vine.
Vines are 12, yeah.
It takes 14.
Okay.
And I get to cleave into the treant.
Oh, you're going to cleave into the treant?
Sure.
Vine took 14, you said?
Yeah.
But you're attacking the wrong vine.
The vine.
The vine you need to attack on the other side of the tree.
Well, there's a dude over here that could use that.
That one.
Oh, okay.
So we need to track both now.
Oh, but you're also.
Oh, no, you're not.
You're still 10 feet away.
All right.
Yeah, he can't hit the one that Soma's chewing on.
Actually, he can.
No, he can't.
No, he's 20 off.
Well, 15 and 12.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
I wanted to be able to cleave into the treant.
So, does a 12 hit the tree?
With the treant or the treant is a 16.
Not hit the treant.
Okay.
All right.
It's actually 15.
Sorry, did I was it?
Did I put 16?
16.
You put 16 in there.
Yes.
I'm just going by what you write in the.
Oh, no, it is 15.
15, it is 15.
Sorry, my bad.
All right.
I believe that.
Sorry, I was looking at the wrong thing.
16.
Is it 16?
It was.
All right.
Are we ready?
Yes, yes.
We still need a Valfine.
Nope.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Valfine.
Yeah.
All right.
So I'll come down here.
So I'm still kind of like outside, right?
No, no, no, no.
You're outside of the range, but you're now inside of the grove.
You have to stay touching the trees.
You stay in the trees.
You're not inside the grove.
Okay.
So if you're on one of the squares where there's a tree, you are outside the grove.
On the perspective of this treant.
So should Brewberry not have gone inside?
No, he can pass all his wisdom saves.
He's good.
Yeah, we could possibly go wrong.
Okay.
So, Valfine, I believe we actually need to try this fairy fire again.
Fairy fire or guiding bolts.
Huh?
Oh, guiding bolt or fairy fire?
Fairy fire is a concentration, and it affects multiple.
So probably it's superior.
I blew the saving throw.
But I need to make sure that I have it as a spell and not just as an ability.
And for some reason, the scroll bar is not working very well for me.
You're cursed.
Elven lineage spells cast as a spell slot.
Which means you can cast them whenever you want, I guess.
Okay.
So first label evocation.
Yeah.
That should do.
All right.
So I blew the saving throw.
So he's covered in his little green thing.
So it is affecting enemies in a radius.
A 20-foot cube.
So 20-foot cube is.
There's only one bad guy, so that doesn't, it's not really that complicated.
I mean, other than the trees.
Can I not get the vines to?
Yeah, so the vines are covered and the treant.
Okay, so we have advantage.
Yes.
You have advantage.
It's like, all right.
We're done with Valfine, right?
Yep.
All right.
Okay.
The Enclave Warrior.
All right.
He actually gave him a Scoutmaster conference.
Rolls his saving throw and manages to not get impacted.
And goes one, two, three, four.
What does he do?
He will shoot with his bow
and miss.
Why isn't he trying to help with the ritual?
Because he's got one hit point.
And if he stays in the area, he will die from the end blows the saving throw, he will die.
Uh-huh.
So, and he noticed that you guys are.
We really need to complete the ritual.
Are you asking him that?
Because there's an answer that is not snarky.
Yeah, I don't understand.
I'm going to go work on the ritual.
I'll probably get obliterated.
He goes, he goes, no, you don't understand.
If we killed, since when we showed up, the treant was weak.
Now it is powerful.
But if we now altogether, we can gang up on the treant and kill it and then perform the ritual sealing the planar rift.
We don't have to.
But if we seal the rift, it doesn't matter if the treant's alive or dead.
Yes, but I'm going to seal a rift.
Whose turn is it?
I believe it's yours.
Lyra's like, are you sure?
I'm sure.
Vukradin.
You introduced yourself, right?
Yes, there's a failure.
One failure down.
Does anybody want to help him?
Which one were you doing?
All right.
She has.
Oh, sleight of hand.
Yeah, I'm not particularly useful at that.
You should get somebody better.
I think it's just if you is help taking action?
Oh, yeah, it is.
All right.
The allies.
I'm just trying to see.
Failure.
I love it.
One failure down.
Get him out of there.
Lyra turns to you and says, Do you know what you're doing with this ritual?
Yes.
I am doing my plus six proficient roll, and I am failing it.
Would you like me to do the plus two instead?
She goes, No need to be snippy.
We're all in this together.
O team intervention.
All right.
The blighted vine.
None of the blighted.
The character cannot perform the same action twice in a row.
Well, that's going to suck.
Okay.
Selma, you're up.
Blighted vine doesn't do anything.
Yeah.
Oh, you are within range of a blade.
I didn't notice that.
I should take some damage because I moved.
Would you stop rolling so high on me?
Can I take some damage?
Because I like winning.
Yeah, roll a d20.
Is it a save or it's just a d20?
Roll a saving throw DC12 wisdom.
Okay.
Failed.
Druids are.
Bards are curious.
All right.
Okay.
And you have disadvantage on your next attack roll.
Well, probably not going to be attacking anything, so that won't be a problem.
Yes, but you have minus three points.
Minus three hit points?
Yes.
Someone took five hit points away from me.
Was maybe that was maybe that was last week.
Okay.
It might have been.
Yeah.
Okay.
None.
All right.
Who's next?
It was the vines, yeah.
All right, Selma, you're up.
The vines hit me.
Four points of damage.
All right, so it takes me down to 24.
All right.
Oh, where is HP current on Selma 24?
So fairy fire is on these guys.
Yep.
All right.
That should make this a little less embarrassing.
Advantage roll.
All right.
That's 12 damage or no.
13 points of damage.
13, yeah.
That's enough to have knocked it out.
Oh, I think I misread my other one.
Plus critical.
Yeah.
Whatever.
That guy was at 12 hit points, right?
So you did.
Yep, he's dead.
All right.
So go ahead and scribble those out or whatever.
Yes, yes.
Let me just do that.
And so now this guy is free number two, I assume.
Yes, he's free.
Hold on.
I have to scribble this guy as well.
All right.
And then I have one more attack, and I may as well just going to enter the doom zone.
It's a wisdom saving throw, is it?
Yes, yes, wisdom saving throw.
All right.
Let me pull up the right character sheet.
Are you shitting me?
Oh, wait.
Don't I have something that I can't get less than a 10 or something like that?
I think so.
I thought there was.
I thought you had one of those.
Something like that.
Yeah, we talked about that.
Only if it's a charisma check.
Yeah, it's like your performance checks or something like that.
Only charisma checks.
All right.
What happens when I miss my saving throw here?
You take three points of damage and three.
All right.
And have disadvantage for your next attack.
But the treant has fairy fire.
Yes.
So they cancel each other out.
Yep.
All right.
Great.
So I did a bite, so then the treant gets the claws and it misses.
Enclave Warrior
two.
I wonder what creature it thinks has that many hit points.
All right.
Next up will be Treant.
Treant goes, Why do you attack me?
I am but a feature of the natural world.
Lyra shouts, You are not, you are a planar abomination.
Treant.
So after she says that to him, he goes, You wish to send me back to where I came from.
She goes, You do not belong here.
So he first uses a bonus action to trap her.
Okay, so she needs to make a second throw.
And she is snared by the Treant.
And then he turns to, I will kill your friends.
And he attacks the.
Oh my gosh, I rolled the one.
And then I rolled the ten.
I will do nothing.
New none of those things.
Lyra shouts, You're planar abomination, you planar abomination.
You have warped the treant that used to guard this forest.
All right.
Who's next?
Brewberry.
Hold on.
Let me add the.
If we're.
Yeah, okay, Brewberry, you're up.
All right.
I'm attacking the last vine.
And I will do it with my fancy thing.
Seven damage on the vine.
All right.
It's got eight hit points left.
Did you forget your advantage for what it's worth?
I did.
Good point.
You might create.
I don't know.
All right, well.
It's worth a shot.
And then cleave into the treant,
which is a 24 to hit.
Damage on the treant.
Hold on, I'm trying to think.
So you have advantage.
But it's able to create disadvantage as a bonus reaction to one attack by suddenly shifting unnaturally and the planar wins.
So your first attack, you don't get advantage on that attack.
That's my only point.
Okay.
Well, I did not need advantage to hit.
All right, okay.
So how much damage did you do?
I applied it 12.
Right.
12.
The treant is very annoyed.
All right.
Valfine, you're up.
Valfine is still concentrating.
And then she will use her crossbow on this vine, try to finish this thing off.
And that's an 18 to hit for four damage.
Yes.
Which is not quite enough.
Okay.
And Lyra.
Lyra.
What does Lyra do?
Lyra looks at the creature and says, This has gone on long enough.
This has gone on long enough.
And she
do she casts moonbeam.
She casts moonbeam.
Where is it?
Five-foot circle, moonbeam, right?
Yeah.
So she casts moonbeam.
And
the third
second level spell.
Fourth level moon.
Second level spell, moonbeam.
All right.
Okay, so it's 2d10 points of damage.
Okay, she makes the same throw.
So 2d10.
Seven points of damage.
All right.
She puts the cylinder down somewhere.
Yeah, oh, I think.
I guess since things aren't moving, it doesn't really matter.
It's just going to sit on the tree.
Yeah, I think I could have chosen a color that was not green.
I don't know if you guys can see the five-foot circle, but it's kind of.
We don't, but it's on top of the bear, the treant, I assume, because there's nothing else.
Yes.
Okay.
That's Lyra, the enclave, guys.
Yes, all right.
So, Lyra did her action.
Um, and so we now sort again Enclave Warrior one.
All right, he will, um, he will shoot an arrow to try to help his buddy across the way.
Don't forget the advantage.
Oh, 2d20, keep high one.
Oh, he hits two 19 for four points of damage.
That's just enough.
All right, everybody's free.
Enclave Warrior number three is free.
All right, okay.
Um, Vukradin, you're up.
Oh, okay.
Let's see here.
We've got is Blighted Vine at four hit points.
No, it's no, it's zero.
It's zero.
They're all gone.
Treant at 98.
I have disadvantage on attack rolls.
Brewberry's got plenty of hit points.
Disadvantage, but very far.
You also have to make your saving throw for if you stay, if you end your turn, you have to make a saving throw against the psychotic psychic madness.
Oh, but I already have disadvantage.
Oh, this would be on top of the disadvantage.
This would be like it would get even worse.
No, no, you just get that.
It's the saving throw versus damage.
I just three hit points.
Oh, I take that down that three points.
Did I miss the saving throw that I was supposed to take?
Yeah, you would miss the saving through wisdom.
Yes, okay.
You made your saving through, I believe.
13.
I think you did.
Can I move here?
Yes, DC12 is a.
All right, can I move next?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I was talking to Gary.
Yes, you can move there.
Okay.
DC16.
Oof, that is tough.
I guess.
Has the treant been doing much damage?
Well, when it hits, it does a lot of damage.
All right.
I guess I'll try command halt on the try command on the treant.
Bam.
Wisdom save.
Yes.
All right.
Wisdom save.
I rolled it.
Did you make it?
Yes, I rolled.
Of course, you did.
All right.
Yep, I will go back to waiting for my turn.
Okay.
All right.
I think I drop form.
Leave wild shape.
Pull my normal me in.
Okay.
And then it'll please me.
What was that?
I was 21.
So.
And I'm going to use the ritual.
The wisdom nature one.
We should probably wait on that so that we can do have advantage on all attempts.
I have advantage on this anyway.
Oh, okay.
Resonate as part of the staff.
All right.
Sure.
Why not?
Why not indeed?
So just a wisdom throw?
Yep.
Wisdom check.
Yeah.
All right.
I beat the 15.
You did it.
I beat it twice.
All right.
That's one and one.
One and one.
Lyra shouts.
Be careful if you make any mistakes.
Any more mistakes might provoke, might cause bad things to happen.
Oh, I believe it.
All right.
So she applauds your, she says she's very happy and she goes, huzzah.
I think that's the only takes the entire action, right?
And my bonus action was to drop form for that matter.
So okay.
So, Treant.
Hi, Lyra.
I'm not a bear.
Lyra goes, you're a druid as well.
Did you make your wisdom saving throw?
Oh, I have to make one just for the being ending turn there, don't I?
Yeah.
Well, at least that one sucked, but the one that mattered was okay.
We can actually take 3.4 points of damage.
Four points or three?
333.
All right, so I made 18.
Three points of damage.
And right.
Okay.
What does the Treant do?
Eeny, meeny, miny, mo.
The Treant's really pissed at the Emerald Enclave folks.
He considers them betrayers of the worst kind.
So he attacks one of the two guys and does 2d6 plus 4.
So she does nine points of damage to the second guy.
And he does.
And he kills him.
So Emerald Enclave person number two is there, and he uses his bonus action to trap number three right where he is so he can't escape.
Who died?
Number two.
Oh, no.
Yes.
He died.
I mean, zero hit points or dead, dead?
Not 21 hit points.
He's dead, dead.
Oh, we don't play with that.
All right.
He's, what am I doing?
He's at zero hit points.
Blue is death save.
How about that?
Number two?
Okay, the tracker is not getting updated.
Okay.
Two is at zero?
Yes.
There you go.
Two is at zero.
One death save.
All right.
Who's next?
Brewberry, you're up.
Okay.
We only have the treant left, yes.
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
So no cleaving.
So we'll just go with this here, and I will no advantage.
Why do I not get a bench?
Because he can deflect one of the attacks, though he attempts to deflect the first one.
You would normally have disadvantage.
Okay.
All right.
So then I have to do a save?
Yes.
Can take three points of damage.
Three points of damage.
What type of damage?
Ooh.
Psychic psychic, yeah.
All right.
Okay.
Enclave warrior two.
He takes a death save.
He fails his second death save.
So he's had two failures?
Yes.
All righty.
All right.
Balthina?
Balthina.
Should I save this dude?
I was going to use my action to save him since my attacks are useless.
Why don't you let me save him?
I don't know that my attacks are any more effective, but I think they will be.
You think so?
Oh, when the treant finished his turn in the moonbeam, didn't he need to take more damage?
Oh, yes, yes, thank you.
Thank you.
He blew his saving throw, so 2d10.
And can we stack moonbeams?
Yeah.
I think you can.
But you can only concentrate on one spell at a time.
Oh, yes, but I haven't cast my moon beam yet.
Oh, perfect.
Two druids.
18 points of damage.
Down to 80.
Yep.
All right, that's good.
It turns out, do you know what the most deadliest combo is?
Two wizards who cast firewall.
Wall of fire.
How is that so deadly?
Because you can get them this way and that way.
And you can occupy a much bigger area of effect.
Yeah, wall of fire is pretty cool.
And then if you could do firestorm, it's even crazier with two high-level clerics.
Should I assume the treant has a bad reflexive?
It's a tree.
Well, it's a tree with interdimensional capabilities.
No.
Don't assume that.
You can try.
All right.
We'll try it.
What are you going to try?
Sacred Flame for eight.
DC.
It actually is not a bad idea because it has a minus one, so it takes eight points of damage.
All right.
I'll play that.
Okay, next is Lyra.
Lyra.
All right.
You know what?
What is Lyra doing?
Okay.
Lyra.
Lyra
casts.
So she turns to the bard.
Are you going to heal?
She points to Emerald Enclave number two.
Can anyone heal him?
Yeah, yeah.
I'll take care of him.
Excellent.
So she goes, in that case, die, you creature of evil.
Hits him with a sacred with a guiding bolt.
Creature of non-neutrality.
Yes.
Guiding bolt.
All right.
So what is the first level guiding bolt?
4d6 worth of damage.
Yeah, she's going to use her second slot.
She's going to do that.
So it's 5d6.
5d6.
15 points of damage.
Nice.
All right.
treant is down to 57.
And is guiding bolted, right?
Yeah.
So double advantage.
It doesn't work that way.
You already have advantage, but yeah.
Enclave Warrior 3.
Enclave Warrior 3 got freed this round, so we have to see it.
He starts the next round.
Okay, so he's no longer trapped.
All right.
Warrior 1.
Enclave Warrior 1.
Yes.
Shoots an arrow and hits for 4 points of damage against the treant.
I've got it.
Okay.
All right.
Vakradin has how much movement?
30 feet.
Perfect.
5, 10, 15, 20.
Okay.
All right.
Number of hit points equal to your level?
That is three.
Hey, it's three more than he had.
He now has three hit points.
He's very grateful.
Instead of zero.
And I can drag him, I assume.
Yes.
So if I go there, then he would go next to me outside the screen.
Thank you.
He says, thank you.
I can do things that don't involve saving throws.
They're much more effective.
Soma.
What?
Soma has our advantage.
Okay, Soma, you're up.
Yeah, we're just going to start stacking the moon beams.
So let's throw them dice.
I blew my saving throw.
Good.
You can take 15 more damage now and probably another 15 at the end of your turn.
Well, 15 times.
Well, we'll see what it comes out to.
But yeah.
So that is 38 left.
Enclave Warrior number three is currently trapped by the treant.
I assume I need to make a saving throw because I'm still in the.
Yep.
And then if you take damage, I do not.
All right.
There it is.
We do not have to deal with the constitution.
You have to do a concept.
Con save.
All right.
So the treant is really pissed.
You moved one of his guys.
His last round, too.
Yeah, so he's going to attack Soma.
I'm back up to 17 AC now.
Let's go.
All right, I'm going to be back on chat.
Yeah, you whiffed.
All right, and he attacks again.
Another whiff.
Come on, you can't hit a turtle.
Just for the record, I have to.
Your luck is finally running out, Kasathas.
Yes, it is finally running out.
All right, now you've got two moon beams to roll for 11.
The first one is I make the first one, but I blow the second one.
So Lyra's moonbeam is 2d10.
All right, you can roll it.
It'll be your moon beam.
It doesn't matter, but sure.
No, no, no, no, no, it is your moon beam.
Because it's the second one.
It's the second one.
It's all right.
Eight.
Eight points of damage.
We got this.
All right.
Brewberry.
Did we deduct the damage on the tree?
Yeah.
Yeah, he's at 30 out of whatever.
Out of 100 million.
All right, then.
We'll just smash it again.
That would be a hit for 10.
No advantage, correct?
Yeah.
All right.
Next is who?
Enclave Warrior 2.
All right.
Ames is Bow.
It's for 4 points of damage.
Okay.
I got it.
All right.
And he goes over here.
Balthina, you're up.
All right.
She is going to do her crossbow.
No.
We're going to do the sacred flame.
Sacred flame?
Sacred flame.
DC 13 ducks.
Oh, right.
I have to roll my saving throw.
I made my saving throw.
Make my saving throws, but I can't hit the save.
All right.
Lira.
Once again, we'll use a guiding bolt, and this time it is an ass.
All right.
Enclave warrior number one.
Fires's bow.
Hits for three points of damage.
Four points of damage.
Vakradin, you're up.
Oh.
Okay.
I no longer have disadvantage.
What should I do?
I should miss.
Ouch.
All right.
I'm good at that.
You know, you had a character who hit all the time, but you got bored of rolling dice and hitting all the time.
So now you have bored of this one, though.
Let's keep going.
All right.
Combats.
I'm getting kind of bored of the combats.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Thorn whip, I guess.
What was the?
I don't know.
Poison spray.
Yeah, that was the best cantrip I had.
Let's go.
Nine more damage on him.
Yep.
That takes him to three.
Ah, dang.
Oh, maybe the Enclave Warrior can finish him.
How many damage did you do?
Nine?
Nine.
All right.
So that does the Enclave Warrior destroy him.
Yes, he dies.
Yay.
He's dead.
The creature is.
It's at the Triassis 16, isn't it?
Anyway.
No, but I've got a plus four to hit.
Oh, okay.
That's kind of what I was doing.
All right.
And map.
We're around.
There we go.
So the save that you made, Wade, which one did you do?
It was in Nature, which adds advantage to the next Arcana check.
Intelligence.
Who has the best intelligence?
I'm only a plus one.
I only have a plus one for me.
Brewberry.
Brewberry can't low anything, roll anything less than a 17 on his wisdom or intellect.
What about Lira?
She's got a plus zero.
Well, it's going to be any of us with a plus one.
Go for it, Dave.
You got advantage.
Sure, why not?
It doesn't matter who rolls it at this point.
I think it does matter.
Okay, well, do you want me to just roll it then?
Here.
Told you.
All right.
Two failures.
Well, that's not good.
We're going to run into the bad sort of this condition.
All right.
Can't win all the quests.
Got to try.
All right.
Okay.
Since then have you decided to be away from this?
Everybody but Balthina, Soma, and Emerald Enclave 1 need to make a saving throw.
What kind?
A psychic blast.
So wisdom.
Yes, wisdom saving throws.
Everybody, but worse.
Am I dead yet?
No.
Damn it.
Seven points of damage.
Why was Soma immune?
No, no, Soma does not.
She doesn't need to make the same throw.
Why doesn't she need to make it?
I'm just curious.
Because she's out of range.
I am?
All right.
Oh, no, no.
I'm sorry.
I thought I was looking at the bear.
Oh, yeah.
The bear is, I'm not bear moment.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, so you need to make the same throw as well.
Yeah, okay.
I mean, not that I want to, but.
No.
All right.
Is that your third failure or second failure?
No, that's your second failure.
That was our second failure on this.
Yeah.
Okay.
How much?
How much damage is it?
Seven damage to everyone who failed?
Yes.
We've got one success and two failures.
All right.
Lira, you know.
Lira looks, this is not good.
This is not good.
Lira, I just want to, I was just wondering, like, your plan was to come in here and you were going to make these six successful ritual actions all on your own.
That was your plan?
With your warrior buddies.
I'm just asking.
What about the A's?
I mean, do you have good bonuses on these things?
Because you were going to come in here.
Because bonuses are pretty low on these things.
She's like, this looks pretty tricky.
Is that what you're going with?
Yeah, and yeah.
Yeah.
Do you want to use your charisma to try to get the truth out of her?
Oh, sure.
Why not?
I mean, we're 10 minimum, right?
I have a 10 minimum on that.
15.
Yep, I got the minimum.
And what's the silver tongue effect?
No, I'll get a 15.
It's the minimum.
I got the minimum.
15.
Okay.
I got an 18.
All right.
Fuck you, Balthina.
Fuck you.
Do you want you surface fillers are so easy to read?
All right.
Just over the record, you're beginning to understand why Balthina's backstory involved her sisters tried to kill her several times.
Yeah, you know, like they were easy to figure out.
Lyra looks at you and goes,
I don't think I thought this through very carefully.
Understatement of the day.
She goes, look, we heard about this rift, right?
And there was talk among the Emerald Enclave if we should do anything.
And some were saying, you know, that we should do nothing, that this was just part of the natural world.
And some were saying this was an unnatural act.
And there was much debate.
And I thought this would be, you know, that the planer, these planar disturbances.
And if the ritual fails, what's going to happen?
Are these natural failures?
Failures looking pretty likely at this point.
Are you suggesting that this is natural and you guys are the interventionists that Adabra warned us about?
She looks at you and goes, Yes, do you mention the name of Adabra or not?
I do because I'm just confused.
I assume that they were, you know, trying to stop this thing that looks wholly unnatural.
No, we are interventionists.
It's the naturalists who want, who think that this is normal.
Oh, fuck this.
Kill her.
What?
No, no, no, no.
She's a future fan.
We want to be allies with all the parties.
Wait, wait, just I want to make sure I did not misspake.
Lyra says the planar rift is unnatural.
And she says those who think it is natural are naturalists.
And those who think the planar rift is unnatural and needs to be closed are interventionists.
Yeah, I got you.
So, yeah, I'm just going to throw the third ritual in this help action.
Huh?
We can use this help action.
You're going to intentionally fail the saving throw?
I'm going to intentionally fail it, yes.
Okay.
So you've decided to ally yourself with the disrupt the naturalists.
All right, who believe that the planar is just part of the natural order?
Apparently, it is.
That's your go.
Okay.
Actually, I guess before I do that, why don't we use that crazy staff ability I got?
Where is it?
Something about detecting things.
We needed the money, man.
There was no money for this quest, remember?
No, no, Dabra was going to give him some money because she realized that he needed money.
We had that discussion.
Let's see.
Yeah, all right.
She suddenly realized that your motivation for money is a pure motivation because it's not for wealth and power.
It's to build a music studio.
Yes.
All right.
So for the staff lets me find unnatural blights and corruptions for a few minutes.
So let's use that once a day today right now.
What do we got?
What you get is that, in fact, all the things that are black, those things are like pinging like crazy.
They're very unnatural.
Right.
So basically, from the perspective of the staff, let me just all the perspective of the staff, the interventionists are the naturalists.
Yes.
What have you wrought, man?
Ah, Christ.
How do I convince Lyra, I guess, of the unnaturalness of all this?
No, no, Lyra believes it's unnatural as well.
Okay.
All right.
So just to be clear.
Interventionists.
Hate planar stuff and want it out.
Naturalists see planar scars as normal.
And staff sees planar stars as unnatural.
Yes.
Staff is an interventionist.
Oh dear.
The staff has betrayed me.
Well, I mean, you're a naturalist?
I thought I was.
I don't know anymore.
I don't know what to believe.
I'm going to law school.
Well, you never really found out what the crux of the debate between the naturalists and the French.
No, apparently I haven't.
So this is a good time to find out.
Yeah, no.
Like, what is the deal?
What do you think is going to happen if we close this off, Lyra?
Lyra goes.
I mean, I don't think we're going to succeed at this point, but.
So Lyra says, Adabra associate, Lyra pauses and explains.
When the War of the Dragons, at the end of the War of the Dragons, the Emerald Enclave fractured into two factions.
Oh, dear.
One faction believed that Tiamat's survival was an abomination and needed to be stopped.
Another faction believed that Tiamat's survival was part of the natural cycle of things, because wasn't Tiamat part of the natural order of the multiverse?
And that in the end, everything would be okay or would be fine.
And so when several of us decided to go, when the interventionists, when the Emerald Enclave decided to go support the armies at the World of the Dragons, the interventionists were outraged and screamed that we had betrayed our calling to preserve natural order.
When Tiamat was defeated, we all tried to accommodate ourselves and be friendly, but there's still a faction of naturalists who see anyone who tries to make sure that the natural order isn't disrupted by planar disruptions as inherently violating the natural order.
And thus they call us interventionists.
I mean, this tree is eating people.
Yes.
Well, she pauses.
Polaris says, trees eating people is, you know, tree, if it is part of the natural order, that, you know, animals eat, but this was.
Trees don't eat people.
Well, that's not natural in any way.
World.
Right.
And she goes, furthermore, these she points to the wells and to the brambles that are very peculiar, animated.
The problem with the tree was that this was a good tree.
It was a tree that took care, prospered the forest.
But ever since the planar scars emerge and she points to the wells, it had become poisoned by some extra planar force.
And the tree used to only eat bad people.
Yes, yes, yes.
The tree, the tree used, she turns to you and says, the tree used to be sustained by sunlight.
It used to be a normal tree.
Okay.
Right.
And as a result of this planar shift, it had become, it was being sustained by interdimensional energies.
Sunlight is kind of a natural.
You would know.
Lyra looks at you as if you're speaking some foreign language that she does.
So, okay.
So just to help you, Wade, just to get you emerald enclave, two groups.
Yeah, no, this is this just can't be.
Like, there's naturalists, and then there's like just rolling over and letting the world get extra.
Remember that deer we met and how out of sorts he felt?
Yeah, he didn't seem to.
You know, we should help him.
He wanted help.
We should help him.
Yeah.
So let's try to clear this out.
All right.
You're going to try to clear it out.
It's okay.
We're going to fail anyway.
Are you glad you did the right thing?
I had the right intention and failed.
Go for it.
I want to see the failure.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Hold on.
So the best.
I don't know.
I have a plus one dex.
Let's go with that.
And we'll have no idea.
I could do another DEX roll.
You've taken that action already.
But I just can't do it twice in a row.
Oh, I see.
Hit a failure.
So I could do another sleight of hand.
Yeah, go for it.
I would have advantage, right?
Somebody can help me.
I'll help.
Yeah, I mean, we have infinite actions at the moment, right?
So, well, I'll be helping.
I made it.
All right.
So we're tier two.
Yeah, you're two and two.
What's the DC?
We're two and two.
All right.
It was 13.
Oh, okay.
Great.
Wait, do you guys need another somebody else who has a high DC?
Is that what you're saying?
What do you need?
High dexterity?
For the sleight of hand check for DC 13.
My DEX is pretty high.
I just, you know, I'm just bad at rolling.
All right, so someone's got to do an intelligence or wisdom, or somebody else could do a dex.
I don't know if somebody else has a good dex.
Well, I mean, I can do my sleight of hand and then I can come back to wisdom.
You said wisdom?
Because I've got plus five wisdom.
Oh, well, then you should do that with advantage.
Yeah.
Wait, is it wisdom safe or like a it's nature or whatever, right?
Yep.
It says nature wisdom.
Nature is an intelligence.
Nature check DC15.
Yeah, nature is intelligence.
Yeah, that's weird.
That doesn't work.
Your quest log says nature wisdom, but nature is intellect.
Get rid of the it's either nature or a wisdom check there.
Oh, you can choose just the raw stat check.
Yes.
Oh, okay.
Raw stat.
That would be plus three.
Okay, with advantage.
Go for it.
Plus three with advantage.
Okay.
Nate it.
So three and two.
Sorry.
I've seen these kind of blights in the underdark.
You know, like so you now advantage on Arcana.
Well, we'd have advantage anyway.
Yeah, we're kind of given that we're all helping each other at this point.
So who wants to?
I've got a plus one.
Anybody?
I'll have to do plus one sleight of hand, I guess.
No, it's the lowest.
Is it just not a plus one?
No, but I mean, it's it'd be wisdom, but my last action was a wisdom one.
There was nature wisdom.
So but you could do the uh that's the thing.
Like, I want to go to the easiest one with the plus one because my strongest one is I can't do twice in a row.
Yeah.
It feels mathematically like the only the best option, which isn't great.
Oh, that's awful.
All right, we botched it.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Hold on.
The Emerald Enclave guy has a plus seven on stuff.
Now he tells us.
We asked him earlier about that.
Plus seven on sleight of hand.
Yeah, sleight of hand.
Well, we already ruined the ritual, so we knew that was going to happen.
Yeah.
I was going to, before Soma rolled it, I was going to have the, you could have one of the unrolled enclaves.
Go ahead.
All right.
We were at three and two.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, we could just do the same roll.
So now we're at now we're at four and two, and then we failed.
So Soma's roll still causes a failure.
We're not going to get to six anyway.
Yeah, it's okay.
So we're four and three.
So unfortunately, the area turns into the wells that grow in size.
And the Emerald Withering Grove is now possessed by a planar rift.
Well, shit.
I don't think we made the world a better place today, guys.
All right, let's get out of here.
Yeah, I think it is just kind of a good opportunity to run.
All right.
Lyra goes, this did not work the way I had hoped.
Well, at least you're alive.
Yes, but we showed up, you were, you know, tree chow.
But we, the intervention, it was supposed to work.
This was going to be a, this was.
She's very distraught.
Yeah, well, inside the world where all the checks fail.
I'm sorry.
Never considered nature wanted us to fail these checks.
Well, if we had more charisma checks, I might actually pass them.
We don't have a lot of charisma checks.
You can't schmoo the planar existence out of existence.
Right.
As you run away, you see a very curious creature
sort of emerge from the planar rift.
No, no.
He's kind of like a phased out creature whose eyes are distorted.
Like as if he's under control of something and he's going around essentially picking things off the ground.
Hmm.
Does anybody want to engage that?
Are we just going to kind of get out of here?
Getting out of Dodge?
I think it's get out time.
We could parley.
I mean, you could try.
He's not.
He seems to be very, he seems to be not engaging with you guys.
And the area, this whole area, not the circular area, is where the whole planar has grown.
It hasn't grown past the edge of these woods.
He's going to hang out.
From the edge of the woods, then, I will inspect and see what he's trying to do.
I'm leaving.
This cannot be good.
That's fine.
Feel free.
He seems to be collecting ingredients.
Collecting ingredients.
What are you doing?
He looks at you and says,
he looks at you, and you realize that he's not under his own control, that somebody feels like there's a puppet controlling.
He's a puppet that's being controlled.
That someone else is in charge.
And he goes and collects some more ingredients.
He picks some stuff off the treant and then he disappears into the well.
Disappears into the well.
Yes.
Just like dives in.
Yes, just dives in.
It's almost as if he came here to cultivate something.
Something was being cultivated here.
Okay.
Put a pin in that.
All right.
And then you run out.
Okay.
And it's 10.38.
Yeah, we're going to go.
The bulls are still kind of like doing their thing.
They're still strong.
What?
The bulls are still doing their planar disruption thing.
Yes.
I'm sorry, what is doing their planar disruption?
Like when he went back, it didn't close behind him or anything.
I don't know.
The wells.
The wells are still disrupting the world.
The wells are still disrupting.
They're not growing.
Roll a nature or investigation or arcana check.
These are all minus one.
So, Soma, your nature gets that some, whoever, that some, these, these planar scars are not accidental.
They're obviously being motivated by it.
Somebody's doing them for a purpose.
Yeah.
It's not just random.
It's not just a random natural event.
Does anybody want to roll an investigation?
No, I'm already in Phandalin.
You're like, I'm not.
This entire forest thing is just not my thing.
We'll have Brewbeary roll an investigation.
He does not notice anything.
He notices that everybody has only one side of bread.
All right.
The madness.
Lyra is like really upset.
She's like, this was supposed to work.
We saved your life, man.
Yeah, no, but let's just go talk to Dabra.
She'll have an idea of what to do.
Yeah.
Next week.
All right.
Bye-bye.
Good night, guys.